# Mazen Bassiso

Jeddah, Makkah, Saudi Arabia



mazen.bassiso@gmail.com



+966537751006



linkedin.com/in/mazen-bassiso-515b00119

## **Summary**

passionate about Technology since childhood & up to date with IT Trends and Cybersecurity! Experienced in Digital Transformation, skilled as a Webmaster developing CMS, E-commerce, CRM & SAAS systems.

Aware of Project management using Agile scrum & operations.

During my free time I get millions of views by creating Tech Tips videos on social media!

## **Experience**

# IT consultant, Webmaster

Ohjiya Group

Mar 2019 - Present (3 years 10 months)

Manage technologies and provide administrative assistance for various systems.

Understand various IT troubleshooting and provide technical support.

Control and monitor data, network access, and backup systems.

Negotiate and communicate with third-party software providers for new software and troubleshooting.

WordPress, SaaS, E-commerce, CRM, CMS, LMS systems web application Development

Backend:

Cloud, Server & Domain management - Security, SEO, ERP, Web Solutions, browsing speed optimization, user levels & authorities

Frontend:

themes, UI, UX & user journey development

Improved Technical projects planning & execution by using Scrum board

managed team working on project + managing client accounts

performed system training sessions for employees



### IT

#### Fast Network est

May 2018 - Feb 2019 (10 months)

Developing an e commerce platform based on WordPress as a part of business digitization configured & managed a stock management & financial plugin in WordPress improved Sales by digital marketing & E-commerce

## **Cyber Security Intern**

GHAT Securenet Sdn Bhd

Jul 2016 - Sep 2016 (3 months) job role .

- \* Penetration Testing techniques
- \* cyber crime investigating

- \* Events and cyber security and hardware training course for government sectors accomplishments
- \* secured a databases and a websites with a vulnerability scan.
- \* earned a legal hacking permission from a huge private company
- \* solved a cybercrime with supervisor

## Technical Assistant

Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation (APU / APIIT) Jul 2014 - Jan 2016 (1 year 7 months) Job Role

- \* Install and configure devices, computers, printers, projectors or operating systems, within university campus.
- \* troubleshoot any device machine software or hardware difficulties inside laps or campus.
- \* reporting laps and internal network status supervisor on a daily basis.

#### **Education**



Asia Pacific University of Technology and Innovation (APU / APIIT)

Bachelor's degree, IT, major Information Systems Security 2013 - 2017

Within my time at APU

- \* learned to accomplish projects assigned within a specific timeline
- \* improved my communication skills to be able to succeed in group work
- \* acquired required skills & knowledge to get my bachelor degree
- \*focused & improved my time management skill

#### **Licenses & Certifications**





Introduction to Cybersecurity 0720 wr - Cisco Networking Academy

1013042366



Introduction to IoT 0720 wr - Cisco Networking Academy

1013042366

Google Ads Search certification - Google

Issued Jun 2021 - Expires Jun 2022 82030970

Google Analytics Individual Qualification - Google

Issued Jun 2021 - Expires Jun 2022

**G** Digital Citizenship and safety - Google 82056075

**Creative Certification** - Google Issued Jun 2021 - Expires Jun 2022 82101170

## **Skills**

WordPress • PHP • Linux Server • Help Desk Support • Penetration Testing • Internet of Things (IoT)
• cPanel • AWS Lambda • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Cloud Applications

### **Honors & Awards**

Volunteer organizing team award - Saudi Aramco

Nov 2011

part of the team to manage and organize summer festival at Saudi Aramco